Jack P. Avery Papers:
Jack P. Avery Papers
1942-1975
Avery, Jack P. (Jack Parrish)
3 boxes (1 linear ft.)
AR238
Special Collections, The University of Texas at Arlington Library
Biographical Note
Jack Parrish Avery was born in 1901 in St. Louis, Missouri. He served as a corporal in the U.S. Army from 1942-1943, and after his honorable discharge was employed for over 25 years as a machinist at General Dynamics.
Scope and Contents
Correspondence, minutes of Neighborhood Action, Inc. (1967-1973) and the Tarrant County Democratic Organizing Committee (1961-1973), photograph, printed material, voter lists, Neighborhood Action News (1968-1971), and miscellaneous memorabilia. Many of the records in this collection reflect Mr. Avery's involvement in political and civic affairs. The minutes (1967-1973) of Neighborhood Action, Inc., of which he was a board member, are included along with the minutes of the Tarrant County Democratic Organizing Committee annual meetings (1961-1971, 1973), board meetings (1967) and steering committee meetings (1965, 1967). Mr. Avery served as treasurer of the T.C.D.O.C. for many years. The collection also contains some material from District 12 Democrats, Texas Liberal Democrats, and the International Association of Machinists and Aerospace Workers, Lodge 776, Fort Worth, Texas. Mr. Avery was a member of all of these organizations.
Provenance
Mr. Avery's papers were donated to the Archives in 1976 by his sister, Mary Avery.
Organization
Materials are arranged alphabetically by subject or document type and thereunder chronologically.
Separated Material
Copies of The Texas Observer for February 14, 1955; October 3 - November 15, 1975, were removed from the collection as these issues are available on microfilm elsewhere in the Library. Published agreements were removed and added to the Agreement file under the following numbers:
(A 1050) Agreement between Consolidated Vultee Aircraft Corporation, Fort Worth Division, and the Federated Independent Texas Unions, Aircraft Local No. 900 - effective May 16, 1947
(A 1051) Agreement between Consolidated Vultee Aircraft Corporation, Fort Worth Division, and the International Association of Machinists, Aeronautical Industrial District Lodge 776 - effective October 13, 1947
Access
Open for research.
Index Terms
These materials are indexed under the following headings in the catalog of The University of Texas at Arlington Library. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons or places should search the catalog using these headings.
Persons
Avery, Jack P. (Jack Parrish)--Archives.
Organizations
Democratic Party (Tarrant County, Tex.)
Tarrant County Democratic Organizing Committee (Tex.)--Records and correspondence.
Neighborhood Action, Inc.--Records and correspondence.
Tarrant County Democratic Organizing Committee (Tex.)
Neighborhood Action, Inc.
Subjects
Neighborhood government--Texas--Fort Worth.
Alternate Titles
Texas Political History Collection
Container List
  - Aerospace Workers Federal Credit Union, 1959-1972 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Note, passbook, statements, form letter.
  - Bond, Julian, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Theater ticket, clippings, booklet, correspondence.
  - Correspondence, General, 1949-1975 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, Multilith machine, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - District 12 Democrats, 1973-1975 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Correspondence, lists, convention materials, printed material.
  - First Primary, Tarrant County, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Correspondence, list, tabulations, printed material, clippings.
  - Fort Worth City Sales Tax Campaign (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Tabulation, list, printed material, clippings, bumper sticker, 1967 (oversize poster in OS151-4)
  - General Election, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Letter, tabulations, clippings, printed material.
  - Labor Legislation, 1950-1958 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    Letter, printed material.
  - Labor Union Activities, 1944-1969 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    Delegate badge, pencil badge, dues books.
  - Labor Union Activities, 1946-1956; 1961-1972, undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
    Correspondence, notices, receipt, minutes, notes, cards, clipping, booklet, questionnaires.
  - Multi-Purpose Training Center, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    Printed material.
  - Neighborhood Action, Inc., Aircor Industries, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    Correspondence, reports.
  - Neighborhood Action, Inc., Budget, 1967-1969 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    Correspondence, financial documents.
  - Neighborhood Action, Inc., By-laws, 1971, undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Neighborhood Action, Inc., Committees, 1967, 1969, undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
    Reports, correspondence, booklets, lists.
  - Neighborhood Action, Inc., Credit Union, 1969-1972 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    Correspondence, booklets.
  - Neighborhood Action, Inc., Meetings, July, 1967 - December, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    Announcements, minutes.
  - Neighborhood Action, Inc., Organization, 1967, undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Neighborhood Action, Inc., Printed Material, 1968-1970 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    Clippings, Christmas cards, announcements, invitation, booklet.
  - Neighborhood Action, Inc., Training Material, 1972, undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
    notice, program, training guide, code of ethics.
  - Personal Documents, 1942-1950, 1957, 1960-1975 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    Christmas cards, wedding invitation, address cards, correspondence, honorable discharge, poll tax receipt, proof of indorsement, driver's license, notice of classification, photograph, certificates, printed material.
  - Political Materials, 1954-1955, 1966-1975 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    Rump Convention material (1956), announcements, printed material, booklets, lists.
  - Political Organizations, 1952, 1961-1966, 1972-1974 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    Correspondence, printed material, notes, invitations, lists, booklets.
  - Tarrant County Democratic Organizing Committee, 1956-1969 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    Constitution, correspondence, lists, note, printed material.
  - Tarrant County Democratic Organizing Committee, Action Course in Practical Politics, 1969, undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
    Correspondence, lists, note, printed material.
  - Tarrant County Democratic Organizing Committee, Annual Meetings, 1961-1964 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    Proposals, obituary, treasurer's report, letter, lists, resolutions.
  - Tarrant County Democratic Organizing Committee, Annual Meetings, 1965-1966 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    Correspondence, resolutions, treasurer's report, list, minutes.
  - Tarrant County Democratic Organizing Committee, Annual Meetings, 1967-1968 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    Correspondence, lists, minutes, treasurer's report.
  - Tarrant County Democratic Organizing Committee, Annual Meetings, 1969-1971 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    Minutes, notice, list, notes, letter, resolution, rental agreement.
  - Tarrant County Democratic Organizing Committee, Annual Meetings, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    Agenda, minutes.
  - Tarrant County Democratic Organizing Committee, Board Meetings, 1961-1971 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    Correspondence, agenda, lists, minutes.
  - Tarrant County Democratic Organizing Committee, Steering Committee, 1961-1970 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    Minutes, notices, lists, letter, notes, agenda.
  - Tarrant County Social and Legislative Conference (Box 2, Folder 17)
    Cash book with financial entries (1953-1956) and copy of play (undated), letter (1950)
  - Tarrant County Voters (Precincts 48, 49), March, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Tarrant County Voters (Precincts 50, 78), March, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Texas Liberal Democrats, 1950, 1954, 1965-1967, undated (Box 2, Folder 20)
    Notices, questionnaire, cards, printed material, invoice, lists, correspondence, proposed constitution.
  - Yarborough, Ralph, 1960, 1970-1975, undated (Box 2, Folder 21)
    Christmas card, correspondence, receipt, program, clippings, lists, questionnaire.
  - Newspapers (Box OS151, Folder 4)
    Neighborhood Action News, Vol. 1, no. 1 - Vol. 4, no. 3 (1968 - October, 1971), poster